import { Component, ElementRef, OnInit, ViewChild } from "@angular/core";
import { FormControl, FormGroup } from "@angular/forms";

import { AssessmentService } from "./assessment.service";
import { question } from "./question";

import { questions } from "./questions";

@Component({
  selector: "app-assessment",
  templateUrl: "./assessment.component.html",
  styleUrls: ["./assessment.component.css"],
})
export class AssessmentComponent implements OnInit {
  constructor(private assessmentService: AssessmentService) {}

  @ViewChild("completeBtn")
  completeBtn!: ElementRef;

  questionList: question[] = [];
  generalQnList: question[] = [];
  technicalQnList: question[] = [];

  timeLeft: number = 0; //30 min - 1800 secs
  interval: any;

  answerForm!: FormGroup;
  answerArray: Array<String> = [];
  answerValue: questions = new questions();

  ngOnInit(): void {
    //Initialize the question form
    this.answerForm = new FormGroup({
      qn0: new FormControl(""),
      qn1: new FormControl(""),
      qn2: new FormControl(""),
      qn3: new FormControl(""),
      qn4: new FormControl(""),
      qn5: new FormControl(""),
      qn6: new FormControl(""),
      qn7: new FormControl(""),
      qn8: new FormControl(""),
      qn9: new FormControl(""),
      qn10: new FormControl(""),
      qn11: new FormControl(""),
      qn12: new FormControl(""),
      qn13: new FormControl(""),
      qn14: new FormControl(""),
      qn15: new FormControl(""),
      qn16: new FormControl(""),
      qn17: new FormControl(""),
      qn18: new FormControl(""),
      qn19: new FormControl(""),
      qn20: new FormControl(""),
      qn21: new FormControl(""),
      qn22: new FormControl(""),
      qn23: new FormControl(""),
      qn24: new FormControl(""),
      qn25: new FormControl(""),
      qn26: new FormControl(""),
      qn27: new FormControl(""),
      qn28: new FormControl(""),
      qn29: new FormControl(""),
    });

    //Load all Questions
    this.questionList = [
      {
        id: 1,
        question:
          "Look at this series: 12, 11, 13, 12, 14, 13, â€¦ What number should come next?",
        options: ["10", "16", "13", "15"],
        answer: "15",
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: "Which word is the odd man out?",
        options: ["trivial", "unimportant", "important", "insignificant"],
        answer: "important",
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question:
          "An Informal Gathering occurs when a group of people get together in a casual, relaxed manner. Which situation below is the best example of an Informal Gathering?",
        options: [
          "A debating club meets on the first Sunday morning of every month.",
          "After finding out about his salary raise, Jay and a few colleagues go out for a quick dinner after work.",
          "Meena sends out 10 invitations for a bachelorette party she is giving for her elder sister.",
          "Whenever she eats at a Chinese restaurant, Roop seems to run into Dibya.",
        ],
        answer:
          "After finding out about his salary raise, Jay and a few colleagues go out for a quick dinner after work.",
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: "RQP, ONM, _, IHG, FED, find the missing letters.",
        options: ["CDE", "LKI", "LKJ", "BAC"],
        answer: "LKJ",
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question:
          "Peter is in the East of Tom and Tom is in the North of John. Mike is in the South of John then in which direction of Peter is Mike?",
        options: ["South-East", "South-West", "South", "North-East"],
        answer: "South-West",
      },
      {
        id: 6,
        question: "Which of the below is not a Java Profiler?",
        options: ["JProfiler", "Eclipse Profiler", "JVM", "JConsole"],
        answer: "JVM",
      },
      {
        id: 7,
        question:
          "Which of these packages contains the exception Stack Overflow in Java?",
        options: ["java.io", "java.system", "java.lang", "java.util"],
        answer: "java.lang",
      },
      {
        id: 8,
        question: "Which of the following is true about servlets?",
        options: [
          "Servlets can use the full functionality of the Java class libraries",
          "Servlets execute within the address space of web server, platform independent and uses the functionality of java class libraries",
          "Servlets execute within the address space of web server",
          "Servlets are platform-independent because they are written in java",
        ],
        answer:
          "Servlets execute within the address space of web server, platform independent and uses the functionality of java class libraries",
      },
      {
        id: 9,
        question: "Which one of the following is not an access modifier?",
        options: ["Protected", "Public", "Void", "Private"],
        answer: "A",
      },
      {
        id: 10,
        question:
          "Which of the following is a superclass of every class in Java?",
        options: ["ArrayList", "Abstract class", "Object class", "String"],
        answer: "Object class",
      },
      {
        id: 11,
        question: "What is .subscribe?",
        options: [
          "Streams data in asynchronously",
          "Streams data in synchronously",
          "Both",
          "None of above",
        ],
        answer: "None of above",
      },
      {
        id: 12,
        question: "What does AOT stand for?",
        options: [
          "Ahead-Of-Time Compilation",
          "Angular Object Templates",
          "Both",
          "None of above",
        ],
        answer: "Ahead-Of-Time Compilation",
      },
      {
        id: 13,
        question: "Router is part of which of the following module?",
        options: ["@angular/core", "@angular/router", "Both", "None of above"],
        answer: "@angular/router",
      },
      {
        id: 14,
        question: "RxJS can be used for?",
        options: ["Browser", "Server Side", "Both", "None of above"],
        answer: "Both",
      },
      {
        id: 15,
        question:
          "Which angular decorator allows us to define the pipe name that is globally available for use in any template in the across application?",
        options: ["pipeName", "pipeDeco", "Pipe", "None of above"],
        answer: "Pipe",
      },
      {
        id: 16,
        question: "Which of the following is not a DDL command?",
        options: ["TRUNCATE", "ALTER", "CREATE", "UPDATE"],
        answer: "UPDATE",
      },
      {
        id: 17,
        question:
          "Which statement is used to delete all rows in a table without having the action logged?",
        options: ["DELETE", "REMOVE", "DROP", "TRUNCATE"],
        answer: "TRUNCATE",
      },
      {
        id: 18,
        question: "Which datatype can store unstructured data in a column?",
        options: ["CHAR", "RAW", "NUMERIC", "VARCHAR"],
        answer: "RAW",
      },
      {
        id: 19,
        question:
          "How many byte counter in BSON is starting with a random value ?",
        options: ["4", "2", "3", "1"],
        answer: "3",
      },
      {
        id: 20,
        question: "Which of the following format is supported by MongoDB ?",
        options: ["XML", "BSON", "SQL", "ALL"],
        answer: "BSON",
      },
      {
        id: 21,
        question:
          "MongoDB is a _________ database that provides high performance, high availability, and easy scalability.",
        options: ["Graph", "Key value", "Document", "ALL"],
        answer: "Document",
      },
      {
        id: 22,
        question: "Which of the following is used to start server in MongoDB?",
        options: ["mongod", "mongo", "start-mongo", "start-mongo.sh"],
        answer: "mongod",
      },
      {
        id: 23,
        question: "When a java script object is sent to java, the runtime engine creates a java wrapper of type_______",
        options: ["JSobject", "java script file", "jquary", "java wrapper"],
        answer: "JSobject",
      },
      {
        id: 24,
        question: "When a java script object is sent to java, the runtime engine creates a java wrapper of type_______",
        options: ["JSobject", "java script file", "jquary", "java wrapper"],
        answer: "JSobject",
      },
      {
        id: 25,
        question: "What is .subscribe?",
        options: [
          "Streams data in asynchronously",
          "Streams data in synchronously",
          "Both",
          "None of above",
        ],
        answer: "None of above",
      },
      {
        id: 26,
        question: "What does AOT stand for?",
        options: [
          "Ahead-Of-Time Compilation",
          "Angular Object Templates",
          "Both",
          "None of above",
        ],
        answer: "Ahead-Of-Time Compilation",
      },
      {
        id: 27,
        question: "Router is part of which of the following module?",
        options: ["@angular/core", "@angular/router", "Both", "None of above"],
        answer: "@angular/router",
      },
      {
        id: 28,
        question: "RxJS can be used for?",
        options: ["Browser", "Server Side", "Both", "None of above"],
        answer: "Both",
      },
      {
        id: 29,
        question:
          "Which angular decorator allows us to define the pipe name that is globally available for use in any template in the across application?",
        options: ["pipeName", "pipeDeco", "Pipe", "None of above"],
        answer: "Pipe",
      },
      {
        id: 30,
        question:
          "Which angular decorator allows us to define the pipe name that is globally available for use in any template in the across application?",
        options: ["pipeName", "pipeDeco", "Pipe", "None of above"],
        answer: "Pipe",
      },
    ];

    //Calculating time based on questions
    //let say, 1 question = 1 min
    this.timeLeft = this.questionList.length * 60;

    //Load General questionList
    this.questionList.forEach((element: any, index: any) => {
      if (index < 5) this.generalQnList.push(element);
    });

    //Load technicalQnList
    this.questionList.forEach((element: any, index: any) => {
      if (index >= 5 && index <= 29) this.technicalQnList.push(element);
    });

    //Start the timer
    this.startTimer();
  }

  startTimer() {
    this.interval = setInterval(() => {
      this.timeLeft--;
      if (this.timeLeft <= 1) {
        clearInterval(this.interval);
        this.showSummary();
      }
    }, 50);
  }

  answeredQn: any = [];
  onSubmit() {
    this.answerArray = [];
    this.questionList.forEach((element: any) => {
      this.answerArray.push(element.answer);
    });
    this.answerValue = this.answerForm.value;
    console.log(this.answerValue);
    this.answeredQnByUser(this.answerValue);

    console.log("Original Answer: ");
    console.log(this.answerArray);
    console.log("User Answer: ");
    console.log(this.answeredQn);
  }

  //Get the answers submitted by user
  totalNoOfQns: number = 0;
  noOfQnsAnswered: number = 0;
  noOfQnsUnAnswered: number = 0;
  getSubmittedQnDet() {
    this.totalNoOfQns = this.questionList.length;
    this.noOfQnsUnAnswered = 0;
    this.noOfQnsAnswered = 0;
    this.answeredQn.forEach((element: any) => {
      element == "" ? this.noOfQnsUnAnswered++ : this.noOfQnsAnswered++;
    });

    console.log("noOfQnsUnAnswered: " + this.noOfQnsUnAnswered);
    console.log("noOfQnsAnswered: " + this.noOfQnsAnswered);

    this.evaluateQns();
  }

  totalMarkEarned: number = 0;
  totalMark: number = 0;
  evaluateQns() {
    this.totalMarkEarned = 0;
    this.totalMark = this.totalNoOfQns * 2;
    this.answerArray.forEach((element: any, index: any) => {
      console.log("index: " + index);
      console.log(this.answeredQn[index]);
      console.log(element);
      if (this.answeredQn[index] === element) {
        this.totalMarkEarned += 2;
      }
    });
  }

  //assigning the answered qn of user in an array
  answeredQnByUser(answerValue: questions) {
    this.answeredQn[0] = answerValue.qn0;
    this.answeredQn[1] = answerValue.qn1;
    this.answeredQn[2] = answerValue.qn2;
    this.answeredQn[3] = answerValue.qn3;
    this.answeredQn[4] = answerValue.qn4;
    this.answeredQn[5] = answerValue.qn5;
    this.answeredQn[6] = answerValue.qn6;
    this.answeredQn[7] = answerValue.qn7;
    this.answeredQn[8] = answerValue.qn8;
    this.answeredQn[9] = answerValue.qn9;
    this.answeredQn[10] = answerValue.qn10;
    this.answeredQn[11] = answerValue.qn11;
    this.answeredQn[12] = answerValue.qn12;
    this.answeredQn[13] = answerValue.qn13;
    this.answeredQn[14] = answerValue.qn14;
    this.answeredQn[15] = answerValue.qn15;
    this.answeredQn[16] = answerValue.qn16;
    this.answeredQn[17] = answerValue.qn17;
    this.answeredQn[18] = answerValue.qn18;
    this.answeredQn[19] = answerValue.qn19;
    this.answeredQn[20] = answerValue.qn20;
    this.answeredQn[21] = answerValue.qn21;
    this.answeredQn[22] = answerValue.qn22;
    this.answeredQn[23] = answerValue.qn23;
    this.answeredQn[24] = answerValue.qn24;
    this.answeredQn[25] = answerValue.qn25;
    this.answeredQn[26] = answerValue.qn26;
    this.answeredQn[27] = answerValue.qn27;
    this.answeredQn[28] = answerValue.qn28;
    this.answeredQn[29] = answerValue.qn29;
  }

  showSummary() {
    this.onSubmit();
    this.getSubmittedQnDet();
    let el: HTMLElement = this.completeBtn.nativeElement as HTMLElement;
    el.click();
  }
}
